So I'm pretty happy because yesterday we had a nice winter storm and you can see that it's pretty white outside.
所以我很高兴，因为昨天我们下了一场漂亮的冬雨，你可以看到外面白茫茫一片。
It's also pretty sunny.
天气也很晴朗。
It's actually brighter on a winter day than it is on a summer day for us here in Canada because the the sun reflects off the snow.
实际上，对于我们加拿大人来说，冬日比夏日更明亮，因为阳光会从雪地上反射出来。
There's a couple things that I need to do today and I'll teach you some English along the way.
我今天有几件事要做，顺便教你几句英语。
One is I need to clean my driveway out.
一是我需要清理车道。
I'm actually going to blow the driveway out with the snow blower and I'm going to do a little bit of sledding with the kids.
实际上，我打算用吹雪机把车道吹干净，然后和孩子们一起玩玩雪橇。
It's actually it's actually hard to walk through this snow right now.
事实上，现在走在雪地里很困难。
I don't know if you can see.
我不知道你能不能看到。
We're a little bit snowed in today.
我们今天有点雪。
When you're snowed in it means that there's so much snow that we can't get our vehicles out.
当你被雪困住时，这意味着雪太大了，我们的车辆无法开出去。
It is a really nice day though it's it's cold it's minus 15 you don't want to be out here too long without bundling up.
虽然天气很好，但还是很冷，零下 15 度，如果不裹上衣服，就别在外面待太久。
So you can see I have my winter hat on which we call a Tuke in Canada.
所以，你可以看到我戴着冬天的帽子，在加拿大我们叫它 "Tuke"。
I got my winter gloves, got my winter boots, got my winter boots on my feet and I got lots of layers on so I'm nice and bundled up to stay warm.
我戴上了防寒手套，穿上了防寒靴，脚上也穿上了防寒靴，我还穿了很多层衣服，这样就可以裹得严严实实，保持温暖了。
so the accumulation that's the amount of snow that came down they said was going to be 10 to 25 centimeters I think here we got maybe about 10 centimeters so when it's
因此，积雪量也就是降雪量，他们说会达到 10 到 25 厘米。
this cold outside you want to make sure that you don't get frostbite frostbite is when your skin actually freezes when it's minus 15 you can safely be outside for
在室外这么冷的天气里，你要确保自己不会冻伤 冻伤是指在零下 15 摄氏度时，你的皮肤会真正结冰。
quite a while an hour or two but you do want to make sure that you're covered up as much as possible when you're out in cold weather.
不过，在寒冷的天气里外出时，还是要确保尽量盖好被子。
We'll go and see if we can get the big tractor started now.
我们现在就去看看能不能把大拖拉机发动起来。
If I lived in the city, I would have to clean my driveway with a shovel or a small snow blower.
如果我住在城市里，我只能用铲子或小型吹雪机清理车道。
Not as fun.
没那么有趣
For me it's a lot more fun to clean it with the tractor.
对我来说，用拖拉机打扫更有趣。
So it's so cold that in order to start the tractor we have to have it plugged in in.
由于天气太冷，我们必须把拖拉机的电源插上才能启动。
We don't plug our cars in in the winter in this part of Canada, but there are parts of Canada where it's so cold that you have to plug your vehicles in at night just to keep them
在加拿大的这个地方，我们冬天不给汽车插电，但加拿大有些地方非常寒冷，晚上必须给汽车插上电，这样才能保证车辆不被冻坏。
warm.
温暖。
There's a small heater inside.
里面有一个小型加热器。
So we do this with things like tractors around here.
所以，我们在这里用拖拉机之类的东西来做这个。
I'm always glad when things start in the winter when it gets this cold.
每当冬天这么冷的时候，我总是很高兴一切都开始了。
So this machine here on the back of my tractor is a snowblower and what it does is it'll bring the snow in here and it'll shoot it out through that piece up there.
我拖拉机后面的这台机器是吹雪机 它的作用是把雪带进来 然后通过上面那块地方把雪吹出去
I'll give you a little video of it working.
我会给你一段工作视频。
That's how you move a lot of snow really really fast.
这就是如何快速移动大量积雪的方法。
So probably won't be very easy to see.
所以可能不太容易看到。
It's very safe to drive a tractor at the same time as running a snowblower.
在驾驶拖拉机的同时操作吹雪机是非常安全的。
So driveways all nice and cleaned out.
所以车道都清理得干干净净。
We'll be able to get the vehicles out now when we need to go to work.
我们现在就能在需要上班时把车辆开出来。
I'm not sure if you can see out there, but we have what are called snow drifts.
我不确定你是否能看到外面，但我们这里有所谓的雪堆。
So snow in the winter will get picked up by the wind after it's on the ground and it will start to drift.
因此，冬天的雪在落地后会被风卷起，开始飘移。
It'll start to build little snow drifts in different areas.
它会开始在不同地区形成小雪堆。
Drifting can be a little annoying because after you've cleaned the driveway, after you've shoveled or blown the driveway out, the wind can fill it back in again.
漂移可能会让人有点恼火，因为在你清理完车道，铲掉或吹掉车道后，风又会把它吹回原处。
So that's never fun because then you have to go and clean the driveway again.
这可一点都不好玩，因为你又得去清理车道了。
I'll probably have to clean the driveway way again a bit later.
过段时间，我可能还得再清理一下车道。
So when it's cold and windy at the same time we have something that's called the wind chill factor and the wind chill factor is it'll feel colder than
因此，当寒冷和大风同时袭来时，我们有一种叫做风寒因子的东西。
it actually is.
实际上就是这样。
So right now it's minus 15 that's the actual temperature but with the wind chill it feels like minus 20.
现在的实际气温是零下 15 度，但加上风寒，感觉就像零下 20 度。
So the real chill factor it actually feels 5 degrees colder and it's cold out here it's so cold in fact that
因此，真正的寒冷系数实际上是感觉冷了 5 度，这里很冷，实际上冷得要命。
my camera only works for about five minutes before it says that it's too cold and then it shuts down on me so I've been outside I think four times now to make this video so
我的相机只能工作五分钟，然后就会提示太冷，然后就关机了，所以为了拍这段视频，我已经在外面跑了四次了。
we're gonna head behind the house right now we have a hill and the hill has a nice covering of snow on it and the kids are back there sledding they have their sleds out there sledding is when
我们要去房子后面，现在我们有一座小山，山上有一层厚厚的雪，孩子们在后面玩雪橇，他们的雪橇就在那里。
you get a sled and you go down a hill you slide down the hill on the sled or to bargain we also sometimes use tobogans in Canada but it's a lot of fun so let's go
在加拿大，我们有时也使用雪橇，但它非常有趣，所以我们走吧。
check it out yeah let's look at the camera hi Bob the Canadian here winter is finally here we're outside doing
快看，快看镜头 嗨，鲍勃，加拿大人，冬天终于来了，我们在外面做什么呢？
some I'm sledding, some tobogganing.
有的人在玩雪橇，有的人在玩雪橇。
I think I'm gonna go down the hill now.
我想我现在要下山了。
Okay, you're going first.
好吧，你先来
Wish me luck.
祝我好运吧
Okay.
好的
Try not to hit the camera on my way down.
下楼时尽量别撞到摄像机。
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
哦，哦，哦，哦
Oh, oh, that hurt a little bit.
哦，哦，有点疼。
That was a good one.
这是个好主意。
Well, hey, Bob the Canadian here.
我是加拿大人鲍勃
Learn English with Bob the Canadian.
和加拿大人鲍勃一起学英语
Thanks for helping me clean my driveway.
谢谢你帮我清理车道。
And for taking a ride down the hill on a sled, don't forget to click the subscribe button below and give me a thumbs up if this video helped you learn some English and I'll see you next week in the next video.
如果你想坐雪橇下山，别忘了点击下面的订阅按钮，如果这个视频帮助你学习了一些英语，请为我竖起大拇指，我们下周在下一个视频里再见。
I'm just super happy that we got some snow.
下雪了，我真是太高兴了。
I think most Canadians like snow, not all of us, but most of us.
我想大多数加拿大人都喜欢雪，不是所有人，但大多数人都喜欢。
Anyways, I'm Have a great day.
总之，我今天过得很愉快。